Now we're going to cover communication
requirements analysis.
So our stakeholders,
the way we get them to
support the project is by
communicating with them.
That is the best way
to build the relationships
with them to get them
to support our project.
So communicating with them is critical and
we need to figure out who needs what,
when, where, why, how.
Think journalism.
Each of our stakeholders.
Individuals or groups of stakeholders,
we need to figure out what they need.
When they need it, in the format,
they need the information.
Okay, so that's really important.
All right, so let's look at the next
slide.
We'll determine the information needs of
each of our stakeholders.
Again, it can be individuals or groups of
stakeholders.
Think journalism.
Who, Needs what, when, where, why,
how.
So, for example, senior executives usually
want high-level details.
Give them the milestones.
Think about the Gant chart.
How we had, if you think back to the
schedule, we had the milestone schedule,
summary schedule, and then detailed
schedule.
Why is it in different formats for the
needs of our stakeholders?
We have to tailor our communications to
our audience.
Okay, to each, again, individual or group
of stakeholders.
So senior executives, they want high
level.
Give them the milestone, significant
points, or events, what's happening.
Don't give them all the details.
They don't have time for all that.
Whereas, you know, middle management might
need summary information.
Whereas our team members, SMEs,
functional managers working on the project
with us, we'll probably need detailed
information.
So these are examples of the communication
requirements needed by level.
But we also want to consider personal
differences, political differences,
cultural differences.
Every one is different.
So we will have to
tailor our communications
depending on what each
individual's needs are.
Okay.
So again, think journalism.
Who needs?
What, when, where, why, how?
Some people don't want information often.
Give me a weekly summary.
Others are going to want details every
day.
You know the type.
Okay, so everybody is different.
So it's really important
that, remember, we
spend at least 90% of
our time communicating.
We've got to tailor, figure out what the
requirements are for
each of our stakeholders.
And their preferred methods of
communication.
whether it's a meeting, whether it's an
email, whatever the case, all right,
and we've got to use active listening all
the while.
We've got to get feedback from those
stakeholders.
Are you getting the information you need
when you need it in the format you need?
We need to find out these things,
all right?
And tailor our communications.
Again, we might have
to change our strategies
or how often the format
they get information.
With that active listening, it also means
getting not only feedback, but making sure
you are engaging with them, that they know
you are actually listening.
That means nodding as they're talking.
Eye contact, if you can, if it can be face
to face, or using that community.
communication technology like Zoom, go-to
meeting, whatever it is you have, okay?
Because only about 7% of communications is
oral.
Most is in the body language and
paralegal, how you say things.
All right.
So that's why it's so
important if you can actually
see someone when you're
communicating with them.
again individuals or groups so that's
really important so nod I'm not really
sure you know question so you can gain
understanding I'm not really sure what you
were saying can you repeat that or say it
in a different way so I can understand
whatever the case is and you might have to
change how you say things so others can
understand so it's really
important the sender has to make
sure the receiver understands
what's being communicated.
That's important.
All right.
So you're definitely going to watch body
language, emotions.
Another part of active listening is not
talking.
You can't listen if you're yapping.
So one of the things you need to do, close
your mouth, listen to what they're saying.
Okay.
And then get feedback.
You might have to repeat what they said.
So let me make sure I understand what you
were saying.
All right.
Any way we can make sure
that we get the requirements, um,
needs for communications
from each of our stakeholders.
Again, each individual or
groups of stakeholders because
you might have 15,000
stakeholders you're dealing with.
Let's say you have an office
consolidation.
Right now you have office.
is all around the world.
If we have 15,000 stakeholders,
we will have to figure
out a way to narrow them
down to key stakeholders as well.
And I know this is discussed
in different lessons, you
know, that we're covering
too, but things to keep in mind.